<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>NLSS Memes Itempack</name>
    <directory>nlss mod</directory>
    <id>848747396</id>
    <description>Adds NLSS themed items to the game! So far this mod includes 39 all new items, 2 new trinkets and 1 new pill effect! Feedback / bug reports are always appreciated!

If you want easy access to all new items, there's a variable called PREVIEW_ITEMS at the top of the main.lua file. Just turn that variable from false to true, and all items will spawn when you start a run!

Items and their descriptions:

PASSIVES:

- Gungeon Master : Tears turn into bullets, damage + shotspeed up
- LaCroix : Health + tears up
- Eye for Aesthetic : Tears up, tears now fire with a small spread, and varying colors and shotspeeds
- The Coin : Gain damage for every enemy in the room
- Cracked Eggshell : Explode tears whenever you get hit
- Tennis : All stats up
- Red Shirt : At the start of a room, enemies have a chance to be charmed immediately
- Mind Flood : Stats up + leave creep whenever enemies get too close
- Twitchy Chatter : Spawns Twitchy Helpers around the room, giving damage for every Helper collected
- Mr Greenman : Glitches around the room, damaging and inflicting status effects on enemies
- Madrinas Coffee : Speed + shotspeed + luck up
- Cobalt's Streak : Gain damage the longer you last without taking damage
- Purple Lord : Your tears turn purple, become piercing and leave a purple creep in their wake
- Ryuka Buddy : Speed up + rooms now stay open
- Golden Hat : Pennies have a 25% of being nickels instead, damage up when at 99 coins.
- Rattler : Shotspeed + Speed down, Damage up
- Loot Hoard : At the end of a floor boss, receive additional rewards
- Poison Mushroom : Tears have a chance to release a poison cloud when hitting an enemy
- Bread with Integrity : HP up, immunity to creep damage
- Spaghetti Island : HP up, heart drop types depend on whether you have full red hearts or not
- Book of Bolegda : Trade heart containers for permanent damage upgrades
- Virtual Bart : Random stats up every room with small chance of all starts down.
- Duality of Chat : Tears have a chance to incite an argument among enemies

FAMILIARS:

- Pet Rock : Follows the player, turning enemies to gold on touch
- Jar of Jellies : Spawns 2 out of 4 possible jellies that follow the player. Jellies have different effects
- Ocean Man : Bounces around the room with a stats up aura
- Ghost Bill : Throws ghost cheetos
- Teratomo : Bounces around + chance to split when touching an enemy
- Scumbo : Feeds off of bad damage, has multiple phases with different effects
- Staggered Stammer : Orbits player, shooting outward with very high damage and shotspeed

ACTIVES:

- The Beretta : Shoots a single, piercing, high damage tear at a very high speed
- Chicken Nugget : Damage up + speed down every time you eat one. Eat as many as you can!
- Murph : Places a black hole that sucks up enemies and attracts tears
- The Stapler : Damage yourself in exchange for max tears for the rest of the room
- Black Glove : Judo Chops enemies, which confuses them and cuts their health in half
- Monster Time Boardgame : Summons Nightmares that fear and damage enemies
- Minus Realm : Turns the current room to the Minus Realm

TRINKETS:

- Marfle-Pop! : Has a chance to obliterate an enemy upon entering a room
- Irradiated Medkit : On next hit: heal all red hearts, gain 1 soul heart and poison all enemies in the room

Credits:
- Custom Phase for code on tear spread (used in Eye for Aesthetic)
- Sinsthar for code on spawning Entities randomly in combat (used in Twitchy Chatter and Mr Greenman)</description>
    <version>1.39</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Active Items"/>
    <tag id="Trinkets"/>
    <tag id="Pills"/>
</metadata>
